<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on Philip Adams</title><link>https://pbada.ms/page/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on Philip Adams</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://pbada.ms/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About</title><link>https://pbada.ms/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pbada.ms/about/</guid><description>Bio I am a software engineer at Microsoft, working on Bing. Before that, I was a Math/CS student at UChicago. I&amp;rsquo;m primarily interested in systems problems, in particular Vector Search/ANN Search.
I&amp;rsquo;m also interested in aviation, photography, functional programming, and backpacking. I may touch on some of these topics on this blog, and you can see some of my photos here.
Contact You can reach me at blog (at) [this domain].</description></item><item><title>Archives</title><link>https://pbada.ms/archives/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pbada.ms/archives/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Photos</title><link>https://pbada.ms/photos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pbada.ms/photos/</guid><description>St. Louis, December 2016 St. Louis, December 2016 St. Louis, December 2016 Gardens by the Bay roof, Singapore, SG, September 2018 Bridge in Jurong Lake Gardens, Singapore, SG, September 2018 Singapore, SG, September 2018 Trains arriving at Chinese Garden MRT station, Singapore, SG, September 2018 LEGO plant in Gardens by the Bay, Singapore, SG, September 2018 Dog in Bukit Brown Cemetery, Singapore, SG, September 2018 Sheep on the Bridle Path, Christchurch, NZ, September 2018 Sheep and a lamb on the Bridle Path, Christchurch, NZ, September 2018 Fur Seal, Kaikōura, NZ, September 2018 Male Chaffinch, Kaikōura, NZ, September 2018 Coast Track, Kaikōura, NZ, September 2018 Coast Track, Kaikōura, NZ, September 2018 Kaikōura, NZ, September 2018 Coast Track, Kaikōura, NZ, September 2018 Coast Track, Kaikōura, NZ, September 2018 Botanic Garden, Wellington, NZ, September 2018 Fushimi Inari Shrine at night, Kyoto, JP, September 2019 Arashiyama Monkey Park, Kyoto, JP, September 2019 Great Blue Heron, Durham, NC, November 2022 Robin, Durham, NC, November 2022 Lake Toya, Hokkaido, JP, July 2023 Bettyhill, Scotland, UK, July 2024 For higher quality copies of these images, contact me.</description></item><item><title>Search</title><link>https://pbada.ms/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pbada.ms/search/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>